試合再開 ゴンが思いついた　レイザーから ボールを取り返す秘策とは？
You will abandon your original plan, and
commit yourself to a baseless assumption? You really believe...
バレーのスパイク？
Smoky Jail, undo!
おい！　あっち！ んっ？ お！
I see you've made your decision. Once I stopped to think about it,
it was pretty simple.
あれは　まさに…。
You used your cocoon after I played my card.
合体！ 分かったぞ　お前らの狙い！
Since you went into hiding
only after learning my agenda, I knew that was your ability, and that it was a trap.
果たして　どちらが勝つか 勝負！
Your lack of reaction when I lifted
my pipe to strike confirmed it.
レイザーのボールを…。
It made no sense that you showed
no sign of reacting at all.
あ…！
Fifteen minutes.
あっ…。 くっ…。
That was how long I expected you to take
やった！
During that time, I intended to slip
through the smoke and move freely.
お！ 止めた！ やったぞ！ ふぅ…。
You trapped me within that barrier
to separate me from the King, yes?
脱帽だな… 俺のパワーを 奴らのセンスが上回った
Meaning, as long as your
prison of smoke was there, your allies would see it and
conclude that I was still inside.
その中核を成したのが あの少年　キルア
I decided to take advantage
ゴンは 俺のボールを止めるため
of that misconception, and
quietly dispose of your friends.
手にオーラを集中 臆すことなく 正確にボールを捉えた
I knew you would hesitate long enough
to give me plenty of time to act.
精神力と集中力は称賛
You thought I'd spend fifteen minutes
waiting in front of an empty cocoon?
ヒソカは　インパクトの瞬間に あの能力でボールを包み込み
You really underestimated me.
ゴンの取りこぼしを防ぐ
No, on the contrary, it appears...
ボールは　はるかかなたへ 飛んで行ってしまったはず
I overestimated you!
２人の間に挟まれ　クッションと 踏ん張りの　ふた役をこなした
He instantly broke himself up into tiny particles?
オーラの 攻防力移動によって もしも　キルアの体のオーラが 少な過ぎれば
If that's how he broke through Smoky Jail,
I wouldn't have seen a thing!
逆に足のオーラが 不十分だったら 踏ん張りが利かず ボールの勢いに負けて
You should have waited longer... Because my strategy was a last resort.
３人とも外野へ 吹き飛ばされていただろう 体と足への攻防力を 何対何で振り分けるか
To be honest, I was upset by the
fact that I'd been trapped.
恐らく　誤差１％以下の精度を 要求されていたはず
Not a very good diversion strategy. You just contradicted yourself.
これほど経験とセンスが 要求される技術は他にない
You made it through the smoke just fine!
経験不足を補って余りある 天才的なセンスによって
At that point, that was all there was to it.
キルアは　この難関を 見事　クリアした
I was under the impression that
you were a more capable soldier...
恐ろしい才能 恐らく 私が　あの域に到達したのは
One who would carry out his original
plan and be faithful to his mission.
２０歳代の後半
However, you made some wild guesses
and removed the barrier.
合体前に倒す
I must thank you.
機は奴らの攻撃の直後
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
その瞬間ならば 奴らに合体する暇はない
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
今の俺なら ボールに押されることなく 受け止めることができる
Deep Purple!
１人ずつ　確実に仕留めてやる
Run!
もっと！
I can't destroy them?
お。
He's invincible?
さっきのが マックスじゃなかったのか
Thank you! Bye-bye! Don't be fooled...
何という…。
He's playing mind games! My decision to attack the
cocoon was the best option.
怪物…
No, the moment I second-guess myself,
I've played into his hands. My next job
ジン　喜べ
is to predict his objective, and stop him...
こいつは間違いなく お前の息子だ キルア　全力で行くよ。
To join up with the rest of the Royal Guard, to find and eliminate my companions, and to reunite with the King! That must be it...
当ったりめぇだ 遠慮したら　ぶっ飛ばすぞ！
His interests are consistent with mine.
最初は　グ！
There's no problem!
ジャン！　ケン！ グ!!
I'll take this!
予想外の威力…　だが捕れる！
He got me... I can't use any other abilities.
しかし捕ればボールの威力で
If Deep Purple is undone,
I'll be completely helpless!
俺の体ごとエリアの外へ 飛ばされるだろう 捕る選択肢は　なし
I'll have to find a way to get by,
using Deep Purple alone.
来い！
Yo, are you
また　レシーブか！
the esper?
方向によるだろ！
What'd you do with Shoot, huh?
あっ！
What?
はじき返した！ ゴン　よけろ！ それでも勝てるんだ！
Eighty-nine Deep Purple puppets... The maximum number I could
produce in my current state.
いや　よけないね！ そんな勝ち方を望む奴じゃ　ない。
I'll use them to support Knuckle as best I can.
なっ！
I see what you're doing...
気絶!?　そうか あれだけのオーラだ
I'll let you hit me once. But in return...
正真正銘 全てを搾り尽くしたんだろう 胸を張っていい お前の勝ちだ　ゴン！
I'll take your life!
なぜ　わざわざ…！
Okay, no one's here.
「完璧に勝つ」だろ？　ゴン。
This is our chance to escape. Let's go.
ん！
I can't get in touch with Leol-sama.
Since my stomach shrunk, that probably
means Cheetu-sama's dead...
おぉ！ また　はじき返した！
And I haven't heard anything from
Flutter, so I guess that's it.
面白い　ラリーの応酬か？
I'll leave to become a Queen!
根比べだ！
I'll make you my second-in-command.
ボールが離れない！
Help...
「バンジーガム」は　ガムとゴム 両方の性質を併せ持つ
Please... get me out of here...
ふっ…　ん！
Help! Oh, Secretary Bizeff...
あっ…。
You're in trouble. I can't move my legs...
レイザー選手　エリア外に 触れた状態での捕球は反則！
Whatever, let's go. This looks dangerous.
アウトです！
What? Wait... Please!
よって　この試合 ゴンチームの勝利です！
I'm going to die!
やった！ すげぇぜ　お前ら。
No can do... I can't move all that.
えっ　最後　どうなったの？
Then, could you call for help? Like, seriously...
完敗だな… そっか　ヒソカが 決めてくれたんだ。
I'm in a hurry to get out of this place! The boss is missing, our link
with the King is gone, and the palace is a mess.
結局　おいしいとこは 全部　持って行かれたな。
I have no reason to stay here!
みんなの力があったからだよ チームの勝利ってやつさ。
I'll give you whatever reward you want! There are mountains of treasure underground!
何か　そのセリフ　似合わないよ。 フフフ…。
If you help me, I'll give you anything you want.
負けたよ　約束通り 俺達は街を出て行く。
So please pull me out!
あっ　そうか。
Where underground?
そういう趣旨だった。 その前に…。
There's an area for the Supreme
Leader beyond the shelter.
ジンについて　質問に答えよう。
I've been managing the treasure inside. I'm the only one with access...
うわっ　痛った！ ったく　むちゃして！ グッチャグチャだわさ！ 両手とも！
You'll give me anything I want?
どこにいるかも分からない。
You'd better keep your promise.
そう…　まぁ　だとは思ってたけど。
Or I'll kill you! Treasure! Treasure!
ただ　昔話でよければ 少し話そうか？
Treasure, treasure, treasure!
うん！　ぜひ！
It's over... This nation is finished.
実は俺も死刑囚だ。
That was clearly proven
人も　あやめている。 捕まってムショに入り 刑が確定し
when the air assault began before
I was able to make any arrangements.
ジンに雇われて　ここに来た。
They're probably calling the Ants biological
weapons, to use them as an excuse...
「世界中に　たった１人 １人だけでも自分を信じてくれる 人間がいれば救われる」と ジンが教えてくれた。
If I'm captured by the Federation, they'll force me to confess for a cover
story and throw me in prison for life, or they'll execute me, so I can't talk.
((したら遠慮しねえで ぶっ飛ばせよ))
I won't let them capture me...
((ヘッ　じゃあ 殺してもいいってことかよ？))
I'm going to escape!
お前の親父は イカレてると思ったぜ。
Now, I'll go back to the palace, evaluate the current situation,
and return to the King.
死刑囚を前に 自分の作るゲームの話を 何時間もガキみてぇに 夢中で話したかと思えば
Though I'm sure that even if I stay with him,
the King will only find me a nuisance.
その死刑囚を雇い 自分の息子と戦わせるなんてな。
Beelzebub!
生かしてもらってると 思ってるんだ！)) ) )
Go forth, my clones...
) )
Identify the location and status of
every person inside the palace!
)
Pouf's Beelzebub was an ability that allowed him
生まれて初めて 自分の名前を 呼んでもらえた気がしたよ。
He was able to control the size
and number of copies produced, and the smaller the copies,
the more he could produce.
ジンがお前の力を信じ 俺にお前を任せてくれたように 俺も　お前の力を信じた。
However, his main body, which served as a control center,
could only be reduced to a bee's size.
だから　全力で打った。 うん　みんながいなかったら 全然かなわなかったもん。
Smoke-man, if you hadn't removed the barrier, my main body could not have escaped.
うん！
My combat capacity would
have been reduced by half.
ゴン　ジンに会えよ。
I'm sure a puppet master such as yourself
うん！
must know the incomparable difference in
strength between a clone and your own body.
ここが　そうよ。
Now that my main body is free,
I have no weaknesses.
窓？
You have lost.
確かに ここからは海岸線が見えるが…。
You should have been more careful.
ここから　どうやって 海神のすみかに行くんだよ。
If you had, then when you realized the cocoon was empty,
you should have wondered
この光が指し示す 海面の真下 そこに海底洞窟があるわ。
And if I had spoken to you
from outside the barrier, you should have wondered whether
that was my real self.
でも　本当は財宝なんてないのよ。 だますようなまねをして ごめんなさい。
The plan I executed was an act of desperation.
そうなのか。 神聖な洞窟だから
I could attempt to confuse your allies,
but my clones are mere husks.
ごく少数の漁師しか その場所を教えてもらえない。 そこから独り歩きした 勝手な　うわさだもの
Assuming that your allies were as strong as you, even if it took a few casualties,
they would have noticed
財宝伝説なんて。
that my clones were fakes!
もちろん　そう言っても レイザー達は信じなかった。
Had you comprehended the truth,
and realized that my main body
「海に生かされている者が 海を汚すようなまねはできない」。 みんな　そう言って 黙ったまま殺されて行ったわ。
remained within the barrier, you would have understood my
ability, and searched for me.
おい　あくまで　これは ゲームの中のシナリオだからな。
If you had done so, I would have had no way to
fight you in my reduced state...
ようやく　また　ここから 海を見ることができるのね。 昇る朝日 漁から戻って来る船
In other words, if you had maintained
the barrier as per your original goal, your allies may have suffered a bit, but you would have been able to defeat me.
七色に変わる水面
And I was ten-percent resolved
to accept that fate.
私にとっては この景色が　何よりの宝。
Your emotions were perfectly
aligned to accomplish that.
よし！　「一坪の海岸線」　ゲット！
I suppose the explosion
must have thrown you off. A pity...
早速　「クローン」で ３枚にしようぜ。
However, I am now free.
うむ　オリジナルを 有する資格は　君達にある。
Next, I will evaluate the situation in the palace!
ん？　ヒソカは 本当に何もいらないの？ ああ　楽しかったからね。
From the start of the mission,
Morel's condition was less than optimal.
俺達と一緒に行動しない？ 「旅団」の動向も気になるし 僕はカード集めに 興味がないからね。 また何かあったら 「コンタクト」で教えてくれよ。
His exhaustion and impatience, combined
with the extreme tension of the situation, clearly led him to the hasty decision
to engage Pouf in a battle of nerves.
「アカンパニー」か「マグネティックフォース」で 飛んで来るから。 あっ！ ん？
However, he arrived at the
perfect time to support Knuckle, keeping him from engaging Youpi alone.
あ！ えっ？ あのウソつき野郎！ ん？
As a result, it could be said that
he made the correct decision
ヒソカが来てから 俺達　「マグネティックフォース」なんて
to remove Smoky Jail at that time.
使ってないよな？ うん。 知ってたんだ　俺達と会う前から スペルカードのこと！
And it was more than simply
a product of coincidence.
あっ！ キルア　ウソつきには 意味のあるウソしか つかないタイプと
It would be valid to say Morel's wealth of
experience played a role in saving him.
意味のないウソをもつくタイプの ふた通りいるの。
Upon entering the palace, Morel had weighed the strength of the enemies
あんたと私は前者　あいつは後者。
against that of his allies.
深く考えると泥沼に　はまるわよ。 うん。
Subconsciously, he knew that they
had underestimated the enemy.
他のプレーヤーが　あなたに対し 「コンタクト」を使用しました。 ゲンスルー！　何の用だ。 まずは おめでとうと言っておこうか。 何のことだ？
When he realized the length of time his allies
could hold out was shorter than anticipated, he was led to attack the cocoon in order
to avoid struggling with the pros and cons of removing Smoky Jail to go help them.
代わりに「一坪の海岸線」をよこせ。 ふざけるな。
Morel's cunning, derived from his knowledge
of the battlefield, saved his comrades.
まっ　俺達に勝てるかどうか 試してみるのも面白いかもな。 取引に応じるなら
The real one's hidden among the fakes,
trying to attack me, right?
１時間後に　マサドラの入り口まで お前１人で来い。
This time, I'll land a counter on you!
「アカンパニー」は 山ほど持ってるからな　ハハハ…。
Five were taken out... I have eighty-four left!
なぜだ？ いつかはバレることだが あまりに早過ぎる
The smoke ones are fake.
アスタ　アマナ マンヘイム　ニック＝キュー スウヘイル　カヅスール。
They feel completely different. When the real one lands a hit, I'll know.
お前らの１５人の 仲間だった連中　そうだろ？
Seventy-five left!
バインダーで確認してみな もう　ここにはいない。
Seventy-two... Seventy...
これは　死亡したか ゲーム内にいないマーク
Pitou and the woman are on the
west tower's second floor.
ゲンスルー！ ん？
Pitou appears to be healing the woman.
誰だ？　お前。 ゴン＝フリークスだ！
A boy, who appears to be an
enemy, is sitting nearby.
俺が相手になってやる！
Three near the entrance to
the underground shelter...
「奇運アレキサンドライト」を 持ってるそうだな。
They may be heading underground. Welfin is behind them.
ツェズゲラの次は　お前らだ。 それとも 今すぐカードを渡しに来るか？
He appears to be following them.
お前が　今　来い！ 相手になってやる！ 俺だって…！
The woman was injured by the dragon spears.
わ！　うわ！ ツェズゲラ　あっちでやってくれ。 あ！
But why doesn't the enemy attack Pitou?
他のプレーヤーが　あなたに対し 「コンタクト」を使用しました。
One in the soldiers' lounge, in the east tower... The human captured a few days ago.
これから　お前の所へ行く。
It will be born soon. Oh, this area's crazy...
フフフ…。
There are lots of enemies.
ガキのほうが 手っ取り早いんじゃないのか？
One, two, three...
恐らく　「一坪の海岸線」も 分け前として貰ってるだろうし。
But Youpi is taking them out quickly.
持ってたとしても それは　クローンのほうだろう。
Youpi and approximately fifty enemies
are in the north area of the palace!
そうだな。
It's the smoke-guy and a bunch of thugs.
ツェズゲラが 観念するとこを見れば
Also, a weird fatso with a spike on its head!
ガキも素直になるだろう。
Unable to determine if it is friend or foe.
ガキを先にして
Is the spike-head Youpi's true power?
その間　ツェズゲラに 回復されるほうが厄介だ。 何せ　シングルの称号を持つプロ 能力も謎だしな。
Only one of the thugs is real,
while the rest are made of smoke. The number of puppets is not increasing
ゲンスルーは 君達の実力を知らない。
because he needs the pipe to make more.
故に　「一坪の海岸線」の オリジナルを持っているのは
It'll take Youpi less than a minute
to find the real one.
俺達のほうだと思っている。
The King is gone! Where is he?
奴らは　オリジナルを 狙っているんだ　俺達のな。 俺達が　できる限り時間を稼ぐ その間に体を治せ。
Everyone, return!
そして 勝てるチャンスがあるとしたら
What's wrong?
君達しかいない。
You're running out of clones.
だが　ゴン。 お前の　さっきの行動は 自分勝手で最も愚かなものだ。
My attacks are too fast for you to get close.
もしも奴らが　お前の挑発に乗り ここへ来ていたら 負傷しているキルアは　どうなる？
Should I leave an opening for
him to come in and attack?
一時の感情で　自分のみならず
Carefully... Act natural.
仲間の命まで 危険にさらしたんだぞ！
Here you go...
ごめんなさい。
Come on!
恐らく１週間　それ以上は無理だ。
He's a fake?
１週間…　短い いや　それも希望的観測だ
Wait...
もしかしたら３日と待たず 俺達を 先に狙って来るかもしれない
You finally figured it out, idiot?
俺は　ツェズゲラと組む お前達は　どうするんだ？
There never was a real one.
時間稼ぎは 同盟が前提にあっての話だろ？ いや　待て ３人と同盟を組むメリットは少ない。
I'll kill you!
すでに奴らは　俺達８人が 組んでいたことを知ってしまった。
There is a real one, right here!
俺達が　おとりとなり 君達が　ゲンスルー組を たたくという作戦も使えない。
No kidding!
ナンバー２と　ナンバー７５ このオリジナルカードを
An aura explosion?
１つのパーティーで持っているのは 非常に危険だ。
From Youpi? Did he really need to use such an ability?
３週間　俺達が時間を稼ぐ。
I'm worried...
もし　それが成功したら
But locating the King is my first priority!
ナンバー７５ 「奇運アレキサンドライト」をくれないか？
You saved me, boss!
おかしいだろ　さっきは １週間が限度って言ってたのに。
If you hadn't set that restriction, I would have snapped and rushed him!
それは　あくまで 逃げ回るだけの場合だ。
Listen to me...
手段を選ばなければ 持久戦に持ち込む自信はある。
I will create only angry clones of you
なるほど　でもナンバー７５なら
when you've lost control of your temper.
カードと交換で 取り方を教えてもいいぜ。 いや　入手方法は知っている。 ただ　ゴレイヌを含めて我々には バインダーに空きがほとんどない。
If that happens, you are to join the clones, and give careful thought to what must be done. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
手持ちカードを全て 村人に渡すという条件クリアは
I got it.
もう不可能なんだ。 ３週間…。
After cooling down and thinking about it, I realized that he wouldn't have taken Shoot.
この時間では キルアの手の回復も足りないし ましてや　ゲンスルーの 戦力に近づくなど
But if Shoot couldn't move on his own,
who would have moved him?
到底かなわない。
Damn... Stop thinking about it!
つまり　この期間内に 何か　てを考えろってことか。
I need to focus on the opponent before me!
そういう状況を想定し　奴らを そこへ誘う準備をしてくれ。
Where... am I?
よし　今から俺達は ゲンスルー組の足止めにかかる。
That's...
どうしてもクリアしたいなら 戦うしかない。
Uh-oh!
うん。
Hurry up!
「アカンパニー」オン！ マサドラへ！
Go in before the entrance is blocked! Damn, Bizeff is my prey!
３週間…　確かに短いわね。
If I knew what powers they had,
I could make a move.
レイザーとの対決に 勝利した　ゴン だが　ボマーの戦闘力は ゴン達の上を行く
Don't come any closer...
果たして　策は生まれるのか
Pouf!